<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>httpd on Blog</title>
    <link>https://miasnikovas.lt/tags/httpd/</link>
    <description>Recent content in httpd on Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Andrius Miasnikovas</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://miasnikovas.lt/tags/httpd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Compiling Apache httpd from Sources</title>
      <link>https://miasnikovas.lt/2010/05/compiling-apache-httpd-from-sources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miasnikovas.lt/2010/05/compiling-apache-httpd-from-sources/</guid>
      <description>This is yet another post on Apache httpd server installation and configuration. I say another because I&amp;rsquo;ve already written about how to install the packaged version of Apachefor two specific linux distros. This time I&amp;rsquo;ll quickly jot down how I configured and compiled Apache for my needs. There are a few reasons to do this. One of the more important ones being to have a newer version of Apache. It seems that prepackaged Apache versions for some linux distributions can be quite out of date.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache HTTP server (SSL) &#43; Tomcat 6.x on Ubuntu and CentOS</title>
      <link>https://miasnikovas.lt/2010/04/apache-http-server-ssl-tomcat-6-x-on-ubuntu-and-centos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miasnikovas.lt/2010/04/apache-http-server-ssl-tomcat-6-x-on-ubuntu-and-centos/</guid>
      <description>The Environment From time to time I need to do some Apache httpd + Tomcat installations on Linux servers and usually they come in different flavors. While you&amp;rsquo;re still experimenting it&amp;rsquo;s a good idea to use a pre-installed Linux on a virtual machine. I&amp;rsquo;m using the free VMware playerto run virtual appliances, a list of which can be found on VMware page. Personally I like the clean Linux installations without any extras, this way you can install anything you need and create multiple virtual machines of the same Linux flavor with different purposes if you need to.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>