<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>free on Blog</title>
    <link>https://miasnikovas.lt/tags/free/</link>
    <description>Recent content in free on Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Andrius Miasnikovas</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://miasnikovas.lt/tags/free/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Free stuff and some R&amp;R music</title>
      <link>https://miasnikovas.lt/2010/05/free-stuff-and-some-rr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miasnikovas.lt/2010/05/free-stuff-and-some-rr/</guid>
      <description>As always there are too many ideas in my head, stuff I want to learn, books and blogs I want to read, things I want to share with others. When there&amp;rsquo;s too much going on it becomes more difficult to write about any of those, but I&amp;rsquo;m trying to become more organized so I&amp;rsquo;ll do my best to post regularly and more often, whenever I have something to say.
I&amp;rsquo;ve found some really cool free online magazines about BSD operating systems and hacking:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free technical books and resources</title>
      <link>https://miasnikovas.lt/2010/02/free-technical-books-and-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miasnikovas.lt/2010/02/free-technical-books-and-resources/</guid>
      <description>Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about how quickly technical books go out of date or sometimes just can keep up with the new versions of software constantly being released. I do like holding in my hands a nice printed book and enjoying the process of reading it, but for IT books it&amp;rsquo;s just a whole different story. You don&amp;rsquo;t usually need to read the entire book cover-to-cover, most often these books are used as references to help solve a specific problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internet TV and video conversion</title>
      <link>https://miasnikovas.lt/2010/01/internet-tv-and-video-conversion/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miasnikovas.lt/2010/01/internet-tv-and-video-conversion/</guid>
      <description>A little while ago I bought an HDTV and was looking for a nice media player and a conversion tool to help me enjoy it. As I already had paid for the TV, I assumed that free software would be nice. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I found that works for me.
The role of the media player or media center was quickly filled by a program called Boxee which is generally described as a cross-platform freeware media center and includes features like social networking, lets you view, recommend and rate the videos you watch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everyday tools</title>
      <link>https://miasnikovas.lt/2010/01/everyday-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miasnikovas.lt/2010/01/everyday-tools/</guid>
      <description>In this post I want to share with you a few tools which in my opinion are really useful. A while ago I found this page called FileHippo that contains a lot of free software and they even maintain older versions which is great for when you&amp;rsquo;re searching for a particular version of some tool and can&amp;rsquo;t find anywhere else. But the really nice thing is that now they have this program called Update Cheker which you can download and install on you machine and it will analyze the software that you have installed and present you with a list of possible updates including the beta versions as a separate section.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A couple of useful resources</title>
      <link>https://miasnikovas.lt/2008/04/a-couple-of-useful-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miasnikovas.lt/2008/04/a-couple-of-useful-resources/</guid>
      <description>A while ago found this great page that aggregates various posts relevant to developers. Just to remind myself and maybe let others know, if you haven&amp;rsquo;t seen it definitely check it out – http://www.dzone.com
Recently I had the need to alter an SVG file that was produced by someone else. Now although you can do this by opening it in a text editor and make the changes by hand, but you would need to know the SVG tags, attributes, etc and more complex graphical changes are just too difficult.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
