<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>python on Blog</title>
    <link>https://miasnikovas.lt/categories/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in python on Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Andrius Miasnikovas</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://miasnikovas.lt/categories/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Automatic Web Server Monitoring</title>
      <link>https://miasnikovas.lt/2011/02/automatic-web-server-monitoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miasnikovas.lt/2011/02/automatic-web-server-monitoring/</guid>
      <description>Hi there! Here&amp;rsquo;s another quick suggestion for all of you out there who have to deal with a lot of web server environments and need to make sure that they&amp;rsquo;re all alive and responsive. Sure there are all sorts of tools for server monitoring and performance tracking, but I found that most of the time you just need to know if the server is up &amp;amp; running. And of course you should be notified if it&amp;rsquo;s not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search for Files on Remote FTP Server</title>
      <link>https://miasnikovas.lt/2011/02/search-for-files-on-remote-ftp-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miasnikovas.lt/2011/02/search-for-files-on-remote-ftp-server/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ll keep this one short. Don&amp;rsquo;t know about you, but I&amp;rsquo;ve always been frustrated about how most FTP clients won&amp;rsquo;t let you search for files on a remote FTP server. I remember I used some client that had this functionality, but this was quite a while ago so I can&amp;rsquo;t even remember the name of it. If someone else knows any lightweight tools that let you do that, please leave a comment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating thumbnails from photos with Python PIL</title>
      <link>https://miasnikovas.lt/2010/04/creating-thumbnails-from-photos-with-python-pil/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miasnikovas.lt/2010/04/creating-thumbnails-from-photos-with-python-pil/</guid>
      <description>This time around I want to share with you a little Python library I found called PIL. If you&amp;rsquo;re a Python developer chances are you already know of it, but I use Python only from time to time, usually to automate some tasks so I was very excited to come across such a library. First thing&amp;rsquo;s first, download PIL and install it. I&amp;rsquo;m using it on a Windows platform so I used the packaged binary version, but you can get the source code and use it on any platform that supports Python.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>tail -f for windows</title>
      <link>https://miasnikovas.lt/2008/05/tail-f-for-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miasnikovas.lt/2008/05/tail-f-for-windows/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a simple implementation of “tail -f” UNIX command equivalent in python. I used it a lot on windows servers to monitor log files. The good thing is that it works over SMB (windows shares).
#!/usr/bin/env python import sys, os, time def main(argv): if len(argv) &amp;lt; 2: print &amp;#34;Usage: tail filename.log&amp;#34; exit(1) try: fp = open(argv[1], &amp;#34;r&amp;#34;) st_results = os.stat(argv[1]) st_size = st_results[6] fp.seek(st_size) while 1: where = fp.tell() line = fp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strings in JAVA</title>
      <link>https://miasnikovas.lt/2008/04/strings-in-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miasnikovas.lt/2008/04/strings-in-java/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago I needed to extract all strings from .java files and also thought that it would be a good idea to keep count how many times a string is used. So I came up with this simple python script. It&amp;rsquo;s kind of a quick and dirty solution, but it met my needs for the particular task.
import sys, os, re from operator import itemgetter files = [] strings = {} exp = re.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
