<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>security on Blog</title>
    <link>https://miasnikovas.lt/categories/security/</link>
    <description>Recent content in security on Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Andrius Miasnikovas</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://miasnikovas.lt/categories/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Private Key PFX to/from JKS Conversion Using OpenSSL and Jetty</title>
      <link>https://miasnikovas.lt/2010/10/private-key-pfx-jks-conversion-using-openssl-and-jetty/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miasnikovas.lt/2010/10/private-key-pfx-jks-conversion-using-openssl-and-jetty/</guid>
      <description>Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching quite a few screencasts which seem to be a really fun way to learn something. This made me want to create something of my own. So for this blog post I&amp;rsquo;m putting up my first attempts at creating screencasts while trying to explain something useful.
When dealing with PKI based application security, one usually encounters different systems on different platforms and making sure they can interact with each other can be quite a hassle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CIS Security Benchmarks</title>
      <link>https://miasnikovas.lt/2010/07/cis-security-benchmarks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miasnikovas.lt/2010/07/cis-security-benchmarks/</guid>
      <description>This one is for the security conscious. If you are performing a hardening procedure for your OS, application/web server, other applications you might wonder how are other people doing that and where can you draw the line by saying that it is secure-enough. A great place of resource in such a case is the CIS Securityspecifically their resources downloadpage. There you&amp;rsquo;ll find a form that allows you to choose and download a whole bunch of security benchmarks for various products like Apache HTTP server, Tomcat, Apple OSX, FreeBSD, Windows OSes, Firefox, MySQL, Oracle and various others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome Integrated PDF Support</title>
      <link>https://miasnikovas.lt/2010/06/google-chrome-integrated-pdf-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miasnikovas.lt/2010/06/google-chrome-integrated-pdf-support/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re using Google Chrome browserfrom the so-called developer channel(i.e. beta version) now you can enjoy the improved PDF support. The thing is that with all the buzz around the PDF format (in)security a lot of companies seem to have taken some steps in providing a more secure user experience for PDF viewing. Since most of the attacks using PDF files are targeted towards the Adobe Reader we&amp;rsquo;ve seen a lot of updates for the viewer this year.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>